<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ApplicationData link="http://www.jmmc.fr/aspro">
  <program name="Aspro" version="0.3b7"/>
  <compilation date="21/09/2009" compiler="JDK 1.5.0_16"/>
  <text>
    <![CDATA[ASPRO is a complete observation preparation tool developed and maintained by the JMMC
    that allows to prepare interferometric observations with the VLTI or other interferometers.
    It allows in particular to simulate the projected baseline evolution during the observations (supersynthesis),
    derive the visibilities for a given object (single star, binaries, user defined FITS image,...),
    and offers many additional useful functions.
    ]]>
  </text>
  <dependences>
    <package name="JSkyCalc" description="Observability constraints based on JSkyCalc by J. R. Thorstensen, Dartmouth College"
                             link="http://www.dartmouth.edu/~physics/faculty/skycalc/flyer.html"/>

    <package name="JFreeChart" description="JFreeChart is a free 100% Java chart library that makes it easy for developers to display professional quality charts in their applications" link="http://www.jfree.org/jfreechart/"/>

    <package name="iText" description="iText is a library that allows you to generate PDF files on the fly" link="http://itextpdf.com/"/>

    <package name="JAXB" description="Java Architecture for XML Binding (JAXB) allows Java developers to map Java classes to XML representations" link="https://jaxb.dev.java.net/"/>

    <package name="SwingWorker" description="backport of SwingWorker included into Java 1.6" link="https://swingworker.dev.java.net/"/>

  </dependences>
  <menubar>
    <menu label="File">
      <menu label="Load" classpath="fr.jmmc.aspro.gui.action.LoadObservationAction" action="loadObservation" accelerator="L"
            icon="/fr/jmmc/aspro/gui/icons/fileopen.png"/>
      <menu label="Save" classpath="fr.jmmc.aspro.gui.action.SaveObservationAction" action="saveObservation" accelerator="S"
            icon="/fr/jmmc/aspro/gui/icons/filesaveas.png"/>
    </menu>
  </menubar>
  <releasenotes>
    <release version="0.3">
      <prerelease version="0.3b7">
        <change>Add one button to normalize the flux weights in the model editor</change>
        <change>Add one preference to choose the default style of display for positions (X_Y / Rho/Theta) in the model editor</change>
        <change>Add the preferences window (displayed from the menu)</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b6">
        <change>New Interferometer Map Plot to display station positions and the chosen baseline.</change>
        <change>One star name can be optionaly given to the star resolver in addition to the coordinates</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b5">        
        <change>Several UI changes to manage HA min / max and the fringe tracker mode fields depending on the selected target
        in the UV Coverage Panel.</change>
        <change>HA min / max and the fringe tracker mode are related to a specific target and persisted in the observation file.</change>
        <change>Added date and time constraints on VLTI Observing Block : date is defined if night restrictions are enabled;
        LST intervals are defined with the target observability (elevation > 30 deg + delay lines + shadowing)
        restricted by the HA min / max defined in the UV Coverage Panel.</change>
        <change>Added VLTI configuration for the period 87 (new baselines) and fixed period 86.</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b4">
        <change>Added VLTI configuration for the period 86 (idem period 85).</change>
        <change>Added VLTI configuration for the future PIONIER instrument (period 86).</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b3">
        <change>Added basic Observing Block for MIDI.</change>
        <change>Fixed the contiguous date interval problem on observability plot.</change>
        <change>Minor corrections on AMBER observing blocks (proper motion and RA/DEC format).</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b2">
        <change>Updated Aspro data model to keep simbad information like RA (HMS), DEC (DMS), Radial velocity, Identifiers and Object types.</change>
        <change>Updated Target tooltip with new information</change>
        <change>Several fixes to convert sexagesimal RA/DEC in degrees (internal). Known problem : the previously saved files can not be
        load anymore.</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.3b1">
        <change>The star resolver now supports RA/DEC coordinates to enter manually a new target
                (useful when simbad is down or no internet connection)</change>
        <change>Missing fluxes used in Observing Block set to -99</change>
        <change>Several minor UI changes for mac OS X platform (10.4 and more)</change>
        <change>Deployment : Pal library is embedded in its own Jnlp file to avoid signing issues</change>
      </prerelease>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2">
      <prerelease version="0.2b5"> <!-- 0.1b11 -->
        <change>Added a transit mark and ticks for the elevation on the observability plot</change>
        <change>Export VLTI AMBER Observing Block (OB) for a single target (simple)</change>
        <change>Disable model image widgets when the current target has no defined model</change>
        <change>Do not use Rho / Theta for the first model in the model editor</change>
        <change>Replace instead of Append behaviour in the parameter table of the model editor</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.2b4"> <!-- 0.1b10 -->
        <change>Added circle and elongated disk models</change>
        <change>Rho / Theta editor instead of X/Y in the model editor</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.2b3"> <!-- 0.1b9 -->
        <change>First release of the model editor with only punct and disk models</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.2b2"> <!-- 0.1b8 -->
        <change>Enhanced UV coverage plot with several gui widgets to control the plot (U-V range, amplitude or phase)</change>
        <change>Better RGB color (LUT) conversion (linear) for visibilities</change>
        <change>Force LUT Color models to be 256 colors wide with black arround minimum value</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.2b1"> <!-- 0.1b7 -->
        <change>Imported Target Model from jmcs</change>
        <change>Corrected several minor style on charts</change>
        <change>Added target Model uv map on the uv coverage plot with zomming supported</change>
      </prerelease>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1">
      <prerelease version="0.1b6">
        <change>Minor bug fixed on UV Coverage plot when the observability displays the baseline limits</change>
        <change>Fixed PDF text rendering to support greek unicode characters</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.1b5">
        <change>UV Coverage plot showing observable ranges (sampling, instrument mode)</change>
        <change>UV Coverage plot showing rise/set tracks</change>
        <change>Star resolver bug fix for empty proper motion and parallax fields</change>
        <change>Added PDF generation for plots</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.1b4">
        <change>Added a best PoPs algorithm for the complete list of targets</change>
        <change>Fixed JMCS Star resolver for targets without proper motion nor parallax</change>
        <change>Added PoP user configuration</change>
        <change>Added CHARA switchyard (beam / station)</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.1b3">
        <change>Added PoP support</change>
        <change>Evaluate the best PoP configuration that gives the best observability range for a single target</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.1b2">
        <change>Added delay line / switchyard / channels in observability plot.</change>
        <change>Added base line limits</change>
        <change>Enhanced GUI to set min elevation / detailed plot ...</change>
      </prerelease>
      <prerelease version="0.1b1">
        <change>Complete rewrite of the ASPRO software as a desktop Java application.</change>
      </prerelease>
    </release>
  </releasenotes>
    <acknowledgment><![CDATA[This research has made use of one of the services of the Jean-Marie Mariotti Center
\footnote{Available at http://www.jmmc.fr}
]]></acknowledgment>
</ApplicationData>
